Okay, so we're going to try to finish up the rest of our functionality here, including
resetting our test and sending that message to users that are on a mobile device.
Okay, so let's jump into the code.
So at the bottom here, we're going to comment out a title, and this is going to be
for reset the test, and we're going to create a function called reset test.
And inside of this, there are a lot of things we're going to need to reset, actually.
And if we minimize some of this here, well actually we're going to need to reference this.
We don't need to reference that.
We are going to need to clear our interval, of course, and we're going to need to reset
our time left to be our original time left.
In this case, I'm going to make it 60 seconds just to show that it is different, and we're
going to need to regenerate our long text.
We want to have a new order of text, a new set of text, and we need to reset all of these
as well, and we need to reset this as well.
So there's lots of this stuff that actually needs to be reset again.
Okay, so let's start with clear interval, and we're going to clear our timer interval,
and then from there our time left is going to be equal to 60, and we need to change everything
that we had in our end test.
You see that we change our timer element to be times up, but we want that to be what we
actually have here.
We're going to go ahead and copy that, and we'll paste that there.
So our timer element text content is going to be the actual time left, and our final score
element, final score element, dot text content is going to be equal to single quotes.
We're going to reset that, and our text container style display is going to be block.
We're going to show that again, so it's the opposite of this.
We are hiding our text container, and then the opposite here we want to hide our try again
button, so I'll just copy that actually, and we'll set that to be none.
And then from there, our total typed is going to be back to an empty string.
Our typing started is going to be false.
Again, it's going to wait for us to actually type something.
Our current care index is going to be zero, and we'll reset our errors as well to be zero.
And even our text container dot scroll left value, we're going to set that back to zero.
And our long text is going to be equal to generate long text.
So this is going to regenerate that long string.
And then from there, we actually might want to have an initialize function.
So initialize the test.
We're going to need this because this is going to actually check if we are a mobile user
or not, and we're going to need to call this when we reset as well.
And for now, we want our text container, inner text is going to be equal to long text.
I'm using text content and inner text interchangeably.
They are effectively the same thing in this case.
And whenever we init, we actually want this to be taking it from the time left.
So you'll notice when I have the time left at six by default, it was taking 60.
So because that's what I have in the HTML, but if you do decide to change it to 30 seconds
or whatever, then we want to actually set that value to be correct to the variable value.
Okay, and that should be good for our init function for now.
So we'll comment out a title.
It's going to allow us start up to actually run that init function.
And so let's just check this part here.
You can see that that's working, it went to six seconds instead of starting at 60.
And we can actually remove this now, because we are calling that in our init, okay.
And now we're going to also add an event listener, try, again, button listener.
And we'll do try, again, button, add event listener, bracket, single quotes, click, comma,
and then reset test.
Okay, so let's give that a try.
All right, and we're going to click and start typing, okay, and you can see I had an
error, so it actually brought down my score as well.
And now if we click try again, you'll see my time left is now 60 seconds, okay, great.
And we have a reset, we have totally different words here.
Awesome, so our reset test is working and our init function is working.
Lastly, we need to add our mobile message.
So if we go back to our code here, let's comment out a title here for detect.
If the device is mobile, so we're going to create a function is mobile device.
And we're going to return a true or false.
So slash, mobile, and then we have a backslash, alt character, I don't actually know
what that's called, Android, it's kind of acting like an or in this case.
And then we have another slash here, and then I test bracket, navigator, user agent, or
is our window inner with less than 800 pixels, because you remember the width for our text
container is 800 pixels, so we want to just make sure it's bigger than 800 pixels.
So this is going to return true or false.
And then make another function here, show message for mobile users, scroll down a bit, function,
go mobile message, and this is going to alter our text container, text content, and it's
going to be equal to this typing, test is designed for desktop use only, okay, and then
on our init, we're going to want to use a condition here.
So if is mobile device, then we want to show our mobile message, else want to just do
our regular init, okay, so that is it for that.
Let's go ahead and check it out, okay, so I'm going to go ahead and put this on the left
side now, and we'll make it a mobile view, and make this a bit bigger, and fit to window,
okay, and you can see that it's already working.
This typing test is designed for desktop use only, okay, awesome.
So that is working there, and if we take this off, and we refresh, you can see it's still
less than 800 pixels, but if we make it, let's see, yeah, that's more than 800 I guess,
yeah, you refresh that, we see that we still have an issue there, so let's go back into
the code and take a look, okay, so here is the issue here, we have to actually call this
as a function, so is mobile device, and we need our brackets there for that to be called
as a function, okay, so you can see now it's already working again, okay, and lastly we're
going to change our six seconds to be 60, so we're going to need to change it up here,
and we're also going to need to change it in our calculate words for a minute, so remember
you can change this to be 30 seconds if you want, but I'm going to go ahead and leave
it at 60, but again, you can change this number, and you'll need to change this number,
and you'll also need to change this number in the reset test, but you can change it to
be however much time you want, you could also do 120 if you wanted to make it a two minute
words for a minute test, it's totally up to you, okay, so that is it, we are done our functionality
here, and it is working great, okay, so I hope you had fun with this project, I know
that I had fun making it, if you want some more content, be sure to check out the rest
of what I have created on the Zero to Mastery Academy, including my advanced CSS bootcamp,
which goes into a lot of depth on how to design your projects so that they look professional.
All right, I will see you next time, bye for now.